<form>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.enabled</id>
        <label>Enabled</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>Keep a DHCP lease alive for the selected CARP virtual IP.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.carpVip</id>
        <label>CARP virtual IP</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>The CARP VirtualIP to keep a lease for. Interface, VHID (chaddr) and IP are derived from it.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.followIp</id>
        <label>Follow dynamic DHCP address</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help><![CDATA[When set (the default), if the DHCP server hands out a different address than the configured VIP, the keeper accepts it and rewrites the CARP virtual IP to match, so the VIP stays online on a dynamic address instead of going down. Both HA nodes converge on the same address automatically because they share the same chaddr (the server gives one lease per chaddr). Pair it with "Sync firewall alias" so outbound NAT and rules follow the new address; note that inbound port-forwards cannot follow a dynamic address (the upstream only routes inbound to a reserved address). Unset to ENFORCE a fixed reservation instead: a different address then raises a mismatch alarm (and, with "CARP failover on lease loss", hands the VIP to the peer) rather than being accepted.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.aliasName</id>
        <label>Sync firewall alias</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help><![CDATA[Optional. The plugin creates and maintains a firewall Host alias with this name, always set to this CARP VIP's current address. Point your outbound NAT translation address (and any firewall rules that must follow the address) at this alias, so they follow automatically when "Follow dynamic DHCP address" changes it (applied by a state-preserving filter reload). NOTE: inbound port-forwards cannot follow a dynamic address (the upstream only routes inbound to a reserved address). The plugin never deletes the alias. See the plugin README.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.demoteOnLeaseLoss</id>
        <label>CARP failover on lease loss</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Enforce mode only. When set, this node demotes itself (handing the CARP virtual IP to the peer) if this keeper stops holding its DHCP lease. Only meaningful with "Follow dynamic DHCP address" OFF (a following keeper adopts a new address instead of losing its lease, so the two are mutually exclusive). When unset (default), the keeper just keeps the lease alive on both nodes redundantly, without affecting CARP.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.runOnlyOnMaster</id>
        <label>Run only on CARP master</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Niche option. When set, the keeper only sends DHCP (holds the lease) while this node is the CARP master for the VIP; on backup nodes it stays running but idle (releases the lease and stands by). Use only for ISPs/DHCP servers that reject two simultaneous clients with the same chaddr. WARNING: this adds a failover gap — the new master must re-acquire the lease (DORA) before the ISP routes the VIP again. Default (unset) keeps the lease on both nodes redundantly, which fails over seamlessly.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.arpNudgeInterval</id>
        <label>ARP nudge interval (s)</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Periodically broadcast an ARP request from the VIP (with its CARP MAC) for the upstream gateway, so the gateway's ARP entry for the VIP never expires. Use when the upstream ignores gratuitous ARP and never re-ARPs an expired entry — the symptom is that traffic NATed to the VIP works right after a CARP event or DHCP exchange, then silently blackholes some minutes later (outbound packets leave, nothing returns). Only sent while this node is CARP master for the VIP. Default: 240 (on) — one broadcast ARP per interval, harmless on gateways that behave normally. Setting 0 disables the nudge entirely: the periodic nudge, the automatic nudge on CARP failover AND the manual nudge button on the status page (the early lease renew on failover is unaffected).]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.arpListenPromisc</id>
        <label>ARP listen in promiscuous mode</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Fallback, default OFF. The keeper listens for the gateway's ARP reply to each nudge and shows on the Status page when the gateway last confirmed reachability; if nudges go unanswered it logs a warning. Normally the reply is captured without promiscuous mode (the CARP master already accepts the VIP's MAC). Enable this ONLY if the Status page shows the nudge is never confirmed on a bound master — some NICs drop frames addressed to a non-primary unicast MAC unless the interface is promiscuous. WARNING: promiscuous mode makes this root daemon receive ALL traffic on the segment, not just its own; leave it off unless you need it.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.chaddrOverride</id>
        <label>chaddr override</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Only if the ISP reservation MAC differs from the CARP virtual MAC. Empty = use the derived CARP MAC.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.vendorClass</id>
        <label>DHCP vendor class</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Optional DHCP option 60. Set only if your ISP requires a specific vendor-class identifier before it hands out a lease. Empty = not sent.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.clientId</id>
        <label>DHCP client-id</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Optional DHCP option 61, sent as an ASCII identifier for the keeper's own DHCP client. Do NOT copy the WAN interface's client-id verbatim, or the server may treat the keeper and the node's own WAN lease as one client. Empty = not sent.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.hostname</id>
        <label>DHCP hostname</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help><![CDATA[Optional DHCP option 12 (hostname). Empty = not sent.]]></help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>keeper.description</id>
        <label>Description</label>
        <type>text</type>
    </field>
</form>
